Guide to the International Advertising Association. International Advertising Exposition exhibitor handouts, 1925-1928 and undated RL.11668
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
International Advertising Association. International Advertising Exposition exhibitor handouts
1925-1928 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
International Advertising Association
RL.11668
0.4 Linear Feet
Advertising trade organization founded in 1905 as Associated Advertising Clubs of America, changing its name in 1926 to International Advertising Association and in 1929 to Advertising Federation of America; the first international exposition was held in July 1928 in Detroit, Mich. Collection includes reprints, print advertisements, brochures, booklets and other printed materials handed out by participant exhibitors representing a variety of fields in the advertising and marketing industry, including apparel, direct mail, electric and neon signs, graphic art, gravure, newspapers, outdoor advertising, photolithography, telephotography, trade and women's clubs, and window show displays. Companies represented include firms from the U.S., Canada and Great Britain, including the Advertising Club of New York, AT&T, Aronsson Printing, Art Gravure, Bausch & Lomb, Capitol Machine, Chicago Daily News, Consolidated Press, Detroit Free Press, Dictaphone, Fairchild Publications, General Outdoor, Jam Handy, Mulford, National Printing & Engraving, and R.F. Heinrich. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Advertising trade organization founded in 1905 as Associated Advertising Clubs of America, changing its name in 1926 to International Advertising Association and in 1929 to Advertising Federation of America; the first international exposition was held in July 1928 in Detroit, Mich. In 1967 a merger of Advertising Federation of America and Advertising Association of the West formed the American Advertising Federation.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The International Advertising Association. International Advertising Exposition exhibitor handouts were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2007.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Burr L. Robbins papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive Advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporation Vertical Files
John Paver papers
Outdoor Advertising Association of America Archives
Roy Lightner Collection of Antique Advertisements
Wunderman Archives
Collection Overview
Collection includes reprints, print advertisements, brochures, booklets and other printed materials handed out by participant exhibitors representing a variety of fields in the advertising and marketing industry, including apparel, direct mail, electric and neon signs, graphic art, gravure, newspapers, outdoor advertising, photolithography, telephotography, trade and women's clubs, and window show displays. Companies represented include firms from the U.S., Canada and Great Britain, including the Advertising Club of New York, AT&T, Aronsson Printing, Art Gravure, Bausch & Lomb, Capitol Machine, Chicago Daily News, Consolidated Press, Detroit Free Press, Dictaphone, Fairchild Publications, General Outdoor, Jam Handy, Mulford, National Printing & Engraving, and R.F. Heinrich. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising -- Clothing and dress; Advertising, Direct-mail -- History; Advertising -- Congresses; Advertising, Newspaper; Advertising, Outdoor; Art -- 20th century -- Exhibitions; Electric signs; Show windows; Women in the advertising industry; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; American Telephone and Telegraph Company; Bausch & Lomb, inc.; Consolidated-Modern Press, Inc; General Outdoor Advertising Company
- Exhibitor Handouts, 1925-1928 and undated; 1
  - Advertising Club of Montreal (Canada)--Canada As Your Market, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Advertising Club of New York--Advertising Club News v. xiii no. 28, 1928 (Box 1)
  - American Telephone & Telegraph (AT&T)--Telephotographs: Some of Their Commercial Uses, undated (Box 1)
  - Angus Company--The Spur (magazine) promotional brochure, undated (Box 1)
  - Aronsson Printing Company--Expansion-Achievement-Progress, undated (Box 1)
  - Art Gravure Corporation--Artgravure Compels Attention, Gets Results, undated (Box 1)
  - Associated Newspapers (Great Britain)--The Golden Scales of Advertising Value: Daily Mail Net Sales, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Bausch & Lomb--The Sales Projector: The Modern Lamp of Aladdin, undated (Box 1)
  - Bellows-Claude Neon Co.--Claude-Neon: The First Real Innovation in Electric Sign Advertising, undated (Box 1)
  - Booth Publishing--The Booth Newspaper Area: The Michigan Market, undated (Box 1)
  - Bourges Service Inc.--Illustrating Simplicity: Bourges Improved Artist Shading Sheets for Color, undated (Box 1)
  - Brownell Photo-Lithograph Co.--Advertising Waste Spaces Reclaimed, undated (Box 1)
  - Capitol Machine--Capitol-Ized Advertising That Really Sells, undated (Box 1)
  - Chicago Daily News--Accurate-Timely-Complete, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Chicago Daily News--Chicago's Two Billion Dollar Retail Market, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Consolidated Press (Canada)--Keeping Pace with Canada's Growth, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Free Press--Promotional booket, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Dictaphone Sales Corporation--Secretaries Say-, 1927 (Box 1)
  - E.J. Costello/The Poster--If Standardized Outdoor Advertising Did Not Exist, 1928 (Box 1)
  - E.W. Husen Co.--Are Letters Advertising?, undated (Box 1)
  - Einson-Freeman Co. Lithographers--F.D. (Francis D.) Gonda articles from Printer's Ink, 1925-1927 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: Demonstration: The "Open Sesame" to the Dealer's Window; Dramatizing the Window Display; Light vs. Motion in Window Display; Putting a Selling Plan Back of the Display; Putting More Sales-Power in Jewelry Windows; The Co-operative Idea in Window Display
  - Einson-Freeman Co. Lithographers--Print advertisements run in Printer's Ink, 1925-1928 (Box 1)
  - Fairchild News Service--Textile/Apparel data folder, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Fairchild Publications--Pointing the Way to Achievement, undated (Box 1)
  - Federation of Women's Advertising Clubs of the World--12th Annual Meeting program, 1928 (Box 1)
  - General Outdoor Advertising Company--"Highspots" All that the Name Implies (illuminated painted bulletins), undated (Box 1)
  - International Advertising Association--Directory of Exhibitors, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Jam Handy Picture Service--The SVE Jam Handy Pocket Explainer, undated (Box 1)
  - John Borman & Son--The Battle of the Giants-And You, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Max Lau Colortype Co.--Marketing with Intelligence!, undated (Box 1)
  - Mulford Company--Blow Bugle Blow: The Inside Story of the Mulford Company, 1928 (Box 1)
  - National Printing & Engraving Co.--Mailer with sample prints, undated (Box 1)
    Includes portraits of President Herbert Hoover and Vice President Charles Dawes
  - R.F. Heinrich--Exhibit of Pen Drawings brochure, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Saturday Night Press (Canada)--This, Sir, Is What We Mean by "The Complete Service", undated (Box 1)